<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Remarks upon the Scotch Act, in a letter to friend.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28885</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99887481</idno>
  <idno type="VID">190444</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240889075</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing R952A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide L.R.305.a.7.[9]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R227719</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99887481</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99887481e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28885)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 190444)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C21:2[45])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Remarks upon the Scotch Act, in a letter to friend.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Whitlock, near Stationers-Hall,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Company of Scotland Trading to Africa and the Indies --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Trading companies --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  Commerce --  Africa --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-11 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:190444:1"/>
            <head>REMARKS upon the Scotch Act, in a Letter to a Friend.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>TO satisfie you that there's such a thing as a <hi>Scotch</hi> Act, for Grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Trade of <hi>India, Africa,</hi> and <hi>America,</hi> to a Company Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tled or to be Settled in <hi>Scotland,</hi> I send you the Printed Copy inclosed.</p>
            <p>And if Reports be true, and we may believe what we hear, the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scription of the said Company is already perfected for the full Sum of 600000 <hi>l.</hi> half whereof is Subscribed by <hi>English</hi> Merchants, and others. And some say, That the Designs of that Company are framed and car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ryed on here in <hi>London;</hi> and Ships are building and buying, and Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goes providing here and Abroad, in order to a Vigorous carrying on of their Trade; others say, That the Interlopers here, are very good Friends with the Managers of the <hi>Scotch</hi> Company, which some take to be the Reason, why they are not heard to find fault with it; which, whether it be, that they are all one, or, that they intend to shelter their Interloping Ships gone to <hi>India,</hi> and now going thither by Licence under that Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany, and so to come for <hi>Scotland,</hi> for these or some other Important Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons to themselves best known; the Interlopers, who are Men that love to Fish in troubled Waters, and hate all Establishments of Company's for Trade, are reconcil'd to this Company, at least so far, as to make no Noise or any Complaint against it.</p>
            <p>Now as to the Opinions of Men about this Company, which you de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sire to know, they differ so much therein, that I am at a loss how to give you any Account of them.</p>
            <p>Some say, That by this Act, <hi>Scotland</hi> is made a free Port for the Trade of Three Parts of the World.</p>
            <p>Some say, That if it be so, in little time they will draw in the other Quarter.</p>
            <p>Some say, That the Riches of <hi>England</hi> have been Purchased by Selling the Overplus of what we do Import from all Parts of the World, more than what we do Consume our Selves to Foreign Nations.</p>
            <p>Some say, That Foreigners will buy none of those Goods of us which we bring home from <hi>India, Africa,</hi> and <hi>America,</hi> so long as they can be supplied with such Goods from <hi>Scotland;</hi> because they shall certainly buy them Cheaper there, seeing the <hi>Scotch</hi> will Pay no Duties upon them, which are very high in <hi>England,</hi> and by Consequence will make our Goods so much the dearer.</p>
            <p>Some say, That the Retailers in <hi>England</hi> will buy few or no Goods, neither brought into <hi>England</hi> by the Traders to <hi>India, Africa,</hi> and <hi>America,</hi> because they will buy them Cheaper in <hi>Scotland,</hi> the Duties being to be Paid upon such Goods which remain in <hi>England,</hi> to the full, nothing be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing re-paid again but upon the Exportation.</p>
            <p>Some say, That it will be impossible to hinder the bringing in of Goods by Land from <hi>Scotland,</hi> by those Pedlars and others, althô the <hi>Pict's-Wall</hi> were re-built much higher than before.</p>
            <p>Some say, They will be brought in by Sea also, and some say, that this <hi>Scotch</hi> Company will in a short time, for these and many other Reasons, destroy the whole Trade and Navigation of <hi>England,</hi> and carry it to <hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now, Sir, if these will be the Consequences of this <hi>Scotch</hi> Act, it appears very formidable, and should require a speedy Remedy; but it may be, some Men may be of another Mind, and I am always for submitting to better Judgments, and am,</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>John Whitlock,</hi> near <hi>Stationers-Hall,</hi> 1695.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:190444:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>